Speaker:
Usually Polymorph is used to
replace layers in your comp, but
Speaker:
we can actually use this to
attach layers to Target layers.
Speaker:
So here, we've got three layers,
each of them animated
Speaker:
differently.
So Crate 1 is animated only with
Speaker:
keyframes, Crate 2 is animated
with a looping wiggle expression
Speaker:
on the Position, Scale, and
Rotation, and Crate 3 has
Speaker:
keyframes on Position and
Rotation, and both of those have
Speaker:
a loopOut("ping pong")
expression – so, a mix of
Speaker:
keyframed and expression
animation.
Speaker:
We have this Cat layer here that
has an expression applied to the
Speaker:
Y Position and the Rotation to
make it do a little dance.
Speaker:
So if I play this through now,
you can see that the crates are
Speaker:
all moving differently.
The cat is dancing.
Speaker:
We want to place a cat in each
of the crates.
Speaker:
So here with Polymorph, there's
a few settings that we'll need
Speaker:
to set in order to be able to do
that.
Speaker:
Layer order: We want to make
sure that the new layer is
Speaker:
placed below the Target layer.
Layer  parent: Yes, we want to
make sure that the new layer is
Speaker:
parented to the Target layer.
Visibility: We want to show the
Target layer.
Speaker:
So the Targets are each of these
crates – we don't want to hide
them,
Speaker:
and we don't want to delete
them. Expressions:
Speaker:
Now as I've said, there are
expressions applied to some
Speaker:
of the crates. And
there's an expression – or there
are expressions – applied to the
cat.
Speaker:
We don't want
the crate expressions to be
Speaker:
applied to the cat. We want
the
Speaker:
cats to keep whatever
expressions are
Speaker:
currently in place,
so here we want to keep
Speaker:
Source expressions only. If I
apply
Speaker:
that now… We don't need to worry
about Track Matte here and we
Speaker:
don't need to worry about
Separate Dimensions. Delete
Source layer:
Speaker:
Yeah, we don't need the original
cat at the end, so
Speaker:
I'm just going to click on Yes
and apply. If I open
Speaker:
my settings here quickly, you
can see that our Source layer is
Speaker:
set to be the last selected
layer. So I'm going
Speaker:
to select the three Target
layers first – so these are our
three
Speaker:
crates. And then also
our cat – so the cat is the last
selected layer; that is going to
Speaker:
be our Source. If I come over
here now and click on Polymorph,
straight
Speaker:
away you can see
that there has been a cat
created
Speaker:
for each of the crates. If I
play this
Speaker:
now, you can see that the cats
are attached. Now, because the
cats
Speaker:
are – or the source layers,
rather – are positioned
Speaker:
to wherever the anchor point of
the Target layer is,
Speaker:
the cats are kind of hidden
a little bit, so I'm just going
Speaker:
to open up the Position
properties and
Speaker:
drag that up a little.
And if I come back to
Speaker:
the
start, you can see now that we
have those three crates, each of
those crates
Speaker:
has a cat attached to it, and we
still have the
Speaker:
cat dancing, keeping its
animation, and the crates are
keeping all of
Speaker:
their respective animations.